No, thanks.
My mom used to say,
"Life is like golgappas.
Your tummy may be full,
but your heart always craves more."
Greetings.
Myself Laal. Laal Singh Chaddha.
Your shoes are so nice!
So clean!
I can almost see myself in them.
My mom used to say,
"Shoes are like an identity card.
Judge a man by his shoes, not his face."
They're old, aren't they?
The thing is…
I love them.
You know I've worn many shoes in life…
but I still remember my first pair.
My mom used to say
they were magic shoes.
Okay, Laal.
Ready?
These are magic shoes, Laal.
Laal…
-try walking.
-Careful.
-Come on.
-Very good.
Go.
Slowly.
There you go. Happy?
I told you his legs are just fine.
It's his mind that has the problem.
Laal!
My name wasn't always Laal.
Laal was my grandpa's name.
The year I was born,
my grandpa went to Pakistan…
to fight a war.
But he never returned.
My great-grandpa…
didn't return from World War II.
And my great-great-grandpa…
didn't return from World War I.
All three of them were called Laal.
Mom was very proud of all three of them.
So, she named me Laal too.
Looking handsome, Laal!
Here you go, ma'am.
The government is offering
big discounts on pesticides.
Use this, it'll double your harvest.
This is Sumati Nandan
reading the afternoon news.
The Prime Minister of India,
Mrs. Indira Gandhi,
has announced an end
to the national emergency.
Finally, the emergency has ended.
Thank God.
Laal, hold this.
-Come.
-Let me help you.
Hey, mind your business.
He's capable. He'll do it.
Listen, Laal.
There's nothing that you can't do.
You don't need anyone's help.
If God wanted to make everyone the same,
he would not have created
so many people, right?
My mom used to explain
everything really well.
She was very smart.
She managed the entire farm by herself.
We lived in Karoli…
about ten kilometers from Pathankot.
We stayed in my mom's family home.
My grandpa, my great-grandpa,
or my great-great-grandpa…
one of them built it.
Phuphi!
Come.
Laal, always remember…
you're absolutely fine.
You're just like the other kids.
You're no different.
Your child is different.
Look, ma'am.
Some children are very intelligent.
Some are normal,
and some are below normal.
Like your Laal.
We cannot enroll him in our school.
Put him in a school for dimwits.
My son is not a dimwit.
He understands everything.
It just takes him a little longer.
He should be given the same
opportunities as other kids.
Look, you already hounded me in school.
Now, you have come
to my house on a Sunday!
I have to go to church.
My maid hasn't come in days.
My cook has eloped.
I'm doing the dishes myself!
You know how difficult
it is to get home help, right?
Please leave, and don't come back.
Not even to school.
Wait here.
I'll come and cook for you every day.
I'll clean your house
and even do the dishes.
What does the child's father do?
He lives abroad.
You seem to be affluent.
Will you really do my dishes,
cook, and clean?
Yes. For as long as my Laal
is in your school.
You don't give up, do you? Here.
Your mother wants the best for you.
Make sure you study hard.
My first day of school…
was the scariest day of my life…
and the best.
Look, Laal.
You have to work really hard.
You have to do better than your best.
Shall I go?
Don't go.
Please.
Hey, come on.
I'll come to get you in the evening.
Please don't leave, Mom.
Just for today.
All right.
I'll wait here.
Once your school is over, come here.
Off you go.
My friend sits here.
Not here! Move along!
It's so strange.
We just can't seem
to control our memories.
I don't remember the moment I was born.
I don't remember my first Diwali…
or the first paratha I ate.
But…
I clearly remember the moment I heard
the sweetest voice…
in the whole wide world.
You can sit here.
Such a pretty face!
I had never seen anything so beautiful.
What are you staring at?
Sit down.
What's up with your legs?
Nothing. I'm perfectly fine.
Where do you stay?
At home.
Are you dumb?
No. I'm perfectly fine.
Her laughter warmed my heart.
What's your name?
Myself Laal. Laal Singh Chaddha.
Myself Rupa. Rupa D'Souza.
From that moment, we became friends.
Rupa lived in Karoli too.
Other than my mom,
no one spoke to me so much.
Rupa and I always used to be together.
Like carrots and peas.
Ever since I saw you
I can't stop looking at you
I just can't seem to get enough
What should I do?
I love chatting with you
I stay up thinking of you
I think I'm going nuts
What should I do?
Life stops when you are not around
And when you're around
I can't take my eyes off you
You are my most favorite person
In the whole wide world
That's how much I love you
What should I do?
Rupa was an amazing magician.
She could pluck a plane
out of the sky and stuff it in her pocket.
She taught me to climb trees,
and I taught her to hang from them.
She taught me to read English,
and I taught her to catch flies.
Life stops when you are not around
And when you're around
I can't take my eyes off you
You are my most favorite person
In the whole wide world
That's how much I love you
What should I do?
Sometimes, we'd just sit
on our tree silently…
waiting for the stars.
Shall we go home?
It's getting dark.
Wait just a little longer, please.
Okay.
I don't know why,
but Rupa never liked going back home.
My mom bought
the first TV in our village.
The whole village came
over to watch the TV.
Rupa…
will you marry me?
India won the World Cup!
India won!
She was my best friend.
My only friend.
Rupa.
My aunt's name was also Rupa.
My aunt's name is Manjeet.
She used to live in Amritsar.
We often visited her.
Once, when we reached Amritsar station,
I saw lots of soldiers there.
Greetings.
Oh, God!
God, help us.
Mom.
Laal…
come with me.
That night, the lights went out…
and didn't come back
for the next four-five days.
Over the next few days,
many explosions happened.
It felt as if the earth was trembling.
Like it was an earthquake.
Mom was really upset.
Don't go out.
Why, Mom?
Well…
there's a malaria epidemic out there.
Don't go out.
During that time,
we didn't leave the house at all.
Son, does your aunt
still live in Amritsar?
No, sir. She moved to Delhi soon after.
The first time I went to Delhi
was to visit her.
I liked to hang out with my cousin
and his friends.
They would dance to film songs.
I liked that.
Look!
Look how the cripple is dancing!
What a clown!
One of the boys really liked my moves.
Hey, why did you stop?
That's a great move.
Show me.
I taught him my favorite move.
He went on to become a very popular actor.
I've seen many of his films.
Kuch Kuch Hota Hai,
Kal Ho Na Ho,
Main Hoon Na,
DDLJ.
Who? Shah Rukh Khan?
Yes, Shah Rukh Khan!
Such a lovely fellow!
He's from Delhi.
-Have you been to Delhi?
-No, I haven't.
You know I've seen every corner of Delhi.
Thanks to my aunt. She was our guide.
This is the PM's residence.
Indira Gandhi lives here.
Forget all that.
Look there. Smile.
Suddenly, one day,
I heard those explosions again.
Indira Gandhi…
the ruler of the world's
largest democracy died today,
shot down by two
of her own bodyguards.
They were Sikhs, taking revenge,
for the invasion of their temple in June.
That evening,
we left to take the train back home.
Suddenly, some people came running
towards our auto-rickshaw.
Oh, Lord!
Madam, take the child and run.
Laal, come on! Hurry up!
I don't know why they
were so angry with us.
We had never even met them before.
Get off!
Kill him!
Let's go.
Mom ran away with me.
Hurry up.
How dare you come back!
Laal, this way.
Stop right there!
Get him!
Hide, Laal. Come on.
Come.
Sit here. Good boy.
Quiet. Keep quiet.
Don't let him get away!
-Get him!
-Kill him!
Lord, please forgive me.
Forgive me.
Maybe they didn't like my long hair.
That's why Mom cut it off.
Mom said that the explosions
we had heard that day
were actually bullets.
Our Prime Minister was killed by them.
Those were terrible days.
Even I was in Delhi at that time.
It's a miracle…
that I'm here today.
Yes! My mom used to say,
"Life is full of miracles."
Some people don't believe in them,
but I can tell you
that miracles do happen.
-Hey, dumbo!
-Got him!
Stupid fellow!
Laal. Hey, Laal.
-What a shot!
-Laal, are you hurt?
Aim for his skull, boys!
Why are you hurting him?
Because it's fun!
-Laal, run!
-Where will the idiot run to?
-Hey, catch him!
-He's running away!
-Catch him!
-Catch the cripple!
You think you can run?
-We won't spare you!
-Where will you go?
You're going to get it good!
Run, Laal, run!
I know you won't believe me,
but I run faster than the wind.
And from that day on,
I ran everywhere.
One day, Rupa didn't come to school.
So, I ran all the way to her house.
Hey! Give me ten rupees!
-I don't have any.
-I know you do.
-I really don't have any.
-Give me money!
I said, give me the money!
-Didn't you hear what I said?
-Laal, do you have ten rupees?
I already gave you whatever I had!
Dad wants it.
I know you have more money!
Where is it? Tell me!
-Speak up!
-That's Rupa's school fees.
I don't care! Give it to me!
Give it to me now!
I won't.
Oh Lord, please make me rich.
-Oh Lord, please make me rich.
-Oh Lord, please make Rupa rich.
-Give me the money right now, or else--
That day, Lord didn't make her rich…
but another miracle happened.
Rupa's mother had eloped
with a Christian man.
And because of that, Rupa's grandma
had broken off ties with her.
After her mother's death,
the police took Rupa to her grandma.
And you know who her grandmother was?
Our home help, Phuphi.
You see? Miracles do happen.
Rupa started staying with us.
I was very happy.
But Rupa remained sad.
Sometimes, she would have nightmares.
Then, she would come
and sleep next to me.
When we got older,
Mom sent Rupa and me
to a college in Delhi.
-Mr. Advani, we are with you!
-There was a huge chariot on the streets.
Lots of people had gathered.
Even we went to check it out.
-With your support,
-Mr. Advani, we are with you!
Mr. Lal Krishna Advani
is embarking on his Chariot Tour.
He's your namesake.
Really?
Lal Krishna Advani.
Even in Delhi,
Rupa and I were always together.
Like carrots and peas.
Got him!
-Hey, what are you doing?
-Hey, Laal.
But those bullies from our village
were also studying in our college.
Why are you throwing stones at him?
-Hey, come on!
-Run, Laal, run!
He's running away.
Start the car.
Get in.
Move it!
Get him!
Run, Laal, run!
How fast can you run?
We're coming, love.
Wait for us!
Almost there!
Oh, no! He's gone!
On your mark, set…
He's flying like a rocket.
Who is he?
Sir, Laal Singh.
He's a dimwit.
Dimwit or not, he runs fast.
Bring him to me.
Our lovely audience,
welcome to the intercollegiate
100-meter race!
Athletes, on your mark!
-Laal Singh!
Set!
-Why isn't he running?
-Run, Laal, run!
Why isn't he stopping?
Laal!
I was really enjoying myself.
I would run a little,
and they'd put me on these steps
and garland me.
Welcome to the interuniversity
100-meter race!
Laal Singh!
Laal!
Run as soon as you hear the gunshot!
Don't stop, boy!
Best of luck! Come on!
-Laal Singh!
-Set.
Run, Laal, run!
-Run, Laal, run!
Hey, stop! Hey, where are you going?
You can stop now!
You won the race!
I joined the National Cadet Corps
in college.
I participated in the parade every year.
And Rupa participated
in some walking contest.
All of a sudden,
the University closed for the holidays.
-Down with the Mandal Commission!
-VP Singh, step down!
Do you remember
what we spoke about yesterday?
I hope you do.
What?
Hello.
Greetings.
Laal, can you get me
some golgappas, please?
Sure.
Where were we?
Thank you.
Rupa loved golgappas.
And I loved Rupa.
Tomorrow, I promise. Not today.
-Rupa, you're breaking your promise.
-Tomorrow.
Please. Just once, Rupa.
No. Not today.
-We'll do it tomorrow.
-Promise?
Yes, I promise--
-Laal!
-Rupa!
Laal, what are you doing?
Stay away!
-Who is this crazy person?
-He isn't crazy. He's my friend.
He's a little slow. Sorry.
Well, stay with him then! I'm leaving!
Harry, wait!
Look what you've done!
Why did you hit him?
He was troubling you.
He wasn't.
Do you know how rich he is?
No, how rich is he?
Rupa, golgappas?
You should've got
the spiced water separately.
You're right.
Laal…
Rupa…
will you marry me?
Laal, I want to go to Mumbai.
I want to become a model
and then an actress.
I'll become famous and very rich.
What will you do, Laal?
Mom says I should join the Army.
But I don't like killing anyone.
So, Rupa went to Mumbai?!
She didn't even answer your question.
Sorry, that's my station.
-I'll have to leave.
-Bye, Uncle.
I was in college around the same time.
I still remember.
We would get so many days off.
Yes, and when there were no holidays…
there would be a malaria problem.
-Malaria?
-Yes.
Mumbai is afire with rioting.
The reason being the demolition
of the Babri Masjid in Ayodhya.
We are receiving reports
of many being injured.
Today, the government
has announced a curfew.
The effects of the Mumbai riots
are being felt nationwide.
Laal Singh Chaddha!
-Hello.
-Laal.
-Mom.
-Son, just stay in your room…
for one week.
What happened, Mom?
Well…
malaria is spreading again.
Oh, okay.
Laal, why didn't you come
to practice today?
Sir, I can't come out.
Malaria is spreading in the country.
Malaria?
He's stupid, sir.
This afternoon, multiple bomb explosions
have shaken the city of Mumbai.
The first bomb went off at 1:30 p.m.
at the Bombay Stock Exchange.
The last one took place
at Hotel Airport Centaur.
Other than that…
Laal Singh Chaddha!
-Laal.
-Mom.
Son, don't get out
of your room for a week.
What happened, Mom?
Well… it's malaria again.
Oh, okay.
Laal, open the door!
You have a race today!
Sir, I can't come out.
Malaria is spreading again.
It's the Nationals! Open up!
No, sir. Mom said no going out.
Talk to him!
I told you he's stupid.
Shut up!
Well, I didn't know it would be so easy
to graduate from the university.
I ran through it.
From the BA program, Laal Singh Chaddha.
Here.
Mom used to say that every man
from our family served in the Army.
So, it was natural for me
to join the Army as well.
Greetings, sir.
Myself Laal. Laal Singh Chaddha.
So? What are you grinning about?
Go, sit!
This seat is taken.
This one too. Go to the back.
I got scared.
I was scolded on the first day
of my training.
I didn't even have a friend there.
Come, sit here.
Do you wear underpants?
Yes.
Which one? A-front or V-front?
I'm not sure, brother.
I wear whatever Mom buys for me.
Undergarments are very
important for a man.
I have been making my own since childhood.
My grandfather was
an undergarments expert.
My name is Balaraju. I'm from Bodipalem.
Everyone calls me Bala.
Myself Laal Singh Chaddha.
I'm from Karoli, Pathankot.
-Everyone calls me Laal.
-Okay.
-Pleased to meet you.
-Same here.
Bala's family was
in the undergarments business.
His grandpa stitched undergarments
for freedom fighters.
His great-grandpa made
undergarments for the British.
And his great-great-grandpa
used to tailor undergarments
for kings and nawabs.
He knew everything about undergarments.
I know everything about undergarments.
After serving in the Army,
I will start my undergarments business.
Laal Singh Chaddha!
Yes, sir!
As an army officer, what is your duty?
Sir, to follow your orders!
Bloody hell. You're a genius.
Genius!
Did you know that you are a genius, Laal?
No, sir. I just found out.
Genius.
Did you hear that?
That's a genius.
You must follow my orders…
I found school tough,
but the Army was really easy.
I just had to remember a few things.
Make a tidy bed.
Stand straight.
And answer every question with…
-Sir, yes, sir!
Brother…
your vest is wrongly cut.
Look, it's loose here and tight here.
Look at mine.
See the fit.
The armhole doesn't stretch.
Very comfortable.
Even your underpants are wrongly cut.
-Oh!
-Look at mine.
My grandpa made it.
It's lovely.
There's not a man in my village…
who doesn't wear undergarments
made by my grandpa.
-The weapon is ready, sir.
-What?
My God! You've broken the record!
-How did you finish it so quickly?
-You said to do it quickly, sir.
Bloody hell! You're a genius! Genius!
Do it again!
Yes, sir!
Genius.
As I was saying…
now, there are newer fabrics available
to make undergarments.
I want to make undergarments
that stay dry even when you sweat.
They'll really sell.
Tell me, brother,
have you ever met a man
who doesn't wear undergarments?
Even a homeless beggar
who doesn't own anything
wears undergarments.
Life isn't comfortable
without good undergarments.
Life is a reflection
of your undergarments.
I want to make all types of undergarments.
One for the winter
and one for the summer.
One for sports and one for sleep.
And a special pair for honeymooners.
Do you want to learn?
Sure.
Bala taught me to make undergarments,
and I made my first vest for him.
I made the second one for Lieutenant.
Genius!
They became very popular,
and I spent every holiday
making them for everyone.
Switch on the TV quickly.
The Miss Universe pageant is on.
The first runner-up is…
Miss Columbia!
That means, Sushmita Sen, Miss India…
you are the new Miss Universe 1994.
Congratulations, Miss India Sushmita Sen,
The stage is yours
for the traditional walk.
Everyone in the Army
gets really lonely at night.
I missed Rupa terribly.
I hadn't heard from her
ever since she had gone to Mumbai.
Laal, look.
Two naked people and a snake.
Lucky snake!
The news said
that Rupa was in trouble.
Apparently, people didn't like
some pictures of hers.
So, the police put her in prison.
I was very worried about her.
I took leave and went to Mumbai.
-Rupa D'Souza!
-Shame! Shame!
-Rupa!
-Hey, sexy!
If you like posing nude,
why don't you strip for me?
Hey, why did you hit him?
Hey, how dare you!
Why did you agree to do this kind
of photo shoot in the first place?
Laal!
What was the need for all this?
You can't keep landing up
everywhere to save me.
He was…
saying bad things about you.
So what?
A lot of people say bad things about me.
Who all will you save me from?
Everyone.
-Really?
-Yes.
Rupa.
Rupa…
will you marry me?
-Do you even know what marriage means?
-Yes, I do.
We're very different
from each other, Laal.
I don't want an ordinary life.
I want to make it really big.
Make a lot of money.
But I don't know where to start.
I really like you, Laal.
But we'll always be just friends.
I should go now.
In a few days,
I'll be posted.
I don't know where.
Listen, be careful.
Don't try to be brave.
If it gets too dangerous, just run.
Got it?
Rupa!
I'll write letters to you every day.
Let's go.
With that…
Rupa left.
Second floor.
Abbas…
this is Rupa.
I had told you about her.
She wants to be a heroine.
Bala and I finished our training in 1995.
He got married a year later.
I had not seen Rupa in four years.
Missing home?
Me too.
My family.
Chithra. Bhawani. Banu.
-Junior Bala.
-Yes.
Junior Bala.
I've been wanting to ask you something.
-May I?
-Yes.
Will you be my business partner?
I've thought a lot about it.
After serving in the Army,
we can start an undergarments business.
I have a foolproof plan. Here.
You take care of manufacturing,
and I'll do the marketing.
We need to invest only 100,000 rupees.
Three sewing machines will cost us 30,000.
You run one machine,
and we'll hire two tailors.
You'll stitch 20 sets
of undergarments a day,
and the tailors will do ten each.
That's 1000 a month. Right?
From the next month onward,
we will easily sell 800 sets.
I think we'll see profits in three months.
Yeah.
-How's my plan?
-Very good.
So, will you become my partner?
-Okay.
-Really?
The following day,
we were sent on a mission.
We were posted in Kargil those days.
Captain told us that some enemies
had entered our territory.
We had to get rid of them.
You don't like to kill anyone, do you?
Me neither.
We're both the same. A perfect pair…
like underpants and a vest.
Brothers forever.
Local shepherds informed us…
that five-six enemy soldiers
had set up a bunker in our territory.
Those local shepherds
came along to guide us.
I thought of my grandpas.
They must have also fought such wars.
Up there.
Papa Oscar 1, go to the left
toward those rocks.
And Papa Oscar 2, toward the right…
Captain sent two teams of six each
to the left and right for covering fire.
In the center was the attacking team.
Bala and I were on the attacking team.
We took cover behind rocks
and made our way up.
Wait.
Let the lowlifes come closer.
We didn't know then,
but the enemies were not just six.
There were many of them.
Fire!
He's hurt.
There was a barrage of bullets.
Fire!
Keep firing!
Kill them all!
There's a whole battalion of them.
Smoke cover!
Boys, give me smoke cover!
Come on!
Sir.
Inform the Bofors Gun Position
to start firing at point 3928.
-In exactly five minutes.
-Roger, sir.
Tango 1! Over!
Go for the gun position!
Bofors fire required
on point 3928 in five minutes.
Roger! Confirming artillery fire
on point 3928 in five minutes!
All teams, fall back.
All teams, fall back! Right away!
Bofors firing to start
on point 3928 in five minutes!
Right after the firing,
we will attack again!
We will take back this camp today!
Laal!
They're falling back.
They're falling back. Follow me.
Give him cover!
Laal!
Hurry up!
Laal, are you okay?
Are you okay? Are you hurt?
Come on, Laal, get up! Let's go!
Bofors firing is going to start
in less than five minutes.
Hurry up, Laal! Come on!
Laal.
Laal!
Run, Laal, run!
I ran.
Just as Rupa had told me to, I ran.
I ran fast, but after some time,
I realized that I was running alone.
Bala?
I didn't know where Bala was.
So, I ran back to find him.
Bala!
Every time I would go back to find Bala,
someone would ask me for help.
I saw my grandpas in every wounded person.
It was one such war
they never returned from.
Laal, where are you going?
Bala!
Are you crazy?
Bofors firing is going
to start any second.
The mountain is dangerous.
Bala! My brother!
Bala.
Laal.
What's this?
You're hurt very badly.
Don't worry. I'm here now.
Bala was hurt very badly.
I carried him and ran.
Out of nowhere, a bee stung me.
I won't let anything happen to you.
Brother…
Why did this happen, Laal?
Laal…
I want to go home.
I want to go to my mother.
Bala.
My brother.
Bala. My brother.
All Bala wanted was
to go back home and start a business.
But he died in Kargil.
That's all I have to say about that.
The war ended a few days later.
Everyone was celebrating our victory.
But I couldn't stop thinking about Bala.
Uncle, was it a bullet?
The bee sting.
Wasn't that a bullet?
Yes.
Where did you get shot?
-On my bum. Would you like to see it?
-No, it's fine.
There's one perk
of getting shot in the bum.
Ice lollies.
I used to have 18 lollies in a day.
Greetings. Myself Laal.
Laal Singh Chaddha.
Hello, Mohammad Paaji.
Ice lolly?
Take it, Mohammad Paaji.
Banu Chandar.
Raman Kumar.
Satyajit Pande.
Moinak Banerjee.
Kulwinder Bakshish.
Manoj Moily.
Hemant Pandey.
Shahid Hussain.
Laal Singh Chaddha.
Laal Singh Chaddha!
All my letters came back.
Perhaps, Rupa hadn't
gone home in many days.
Yes, Rohit. Done.
We'll shoot in Switzerland.
Okay, bye.
Sir, good news.
We've got Rohit Kumar's
dates from next month.
-Congratulations!
-Cheers!
Cheers!
-Congratulations, Abbas.
-Who'd dare turn Abbas down!
I'm the heroine in this film, right?
Do you want to be Rohit's heroine or mine?
Tell me.
Boss has got style.
Drama even in romance.
I'm your heroine, of course.
Wow!
That's true love.
Go, get me a drink.
Sir, you know what?
Priya is pretty popular nowadays.
Yes, Priya will be good.
Call her.
Has anyone seen that local Mohammad?
He's missing since morning.
Something's wrong.
I can't find his record.
The information he gave is incorrect.
And now, he's missing.
Whom did you save, Laal?
Yes, sir. Yes.
Naik Laal Singh Chaddha.
The Commanding Officer wants to see you.
Naik Laal Singh…
you are being awarded
the Veer Chakra for saving five lives.
You must head to Delhi.
Yes, sir.
How is your butt, by the way?
It hurts sometimes, sir.
Your medical category
has been permanently downgraded.
You can't fight in a war again.
You can ask them to discharge you
from the Army on medical grounds.
I will approve it.
Until then, be the assistant coach
of our running team.
Yes, sir.
Well done, my boy.
The nation is proud of you.
Thank you, sir.
In broad daylight,
midst of raining bullets,
and without a care for his own life…
Naik Laal Singh Chaddha
saved five lives.
The Indian Army salutes this bravery.
Naik Laal Singh Chaddha.
That's my son.
Your grandpa would've
been very proud today.
What do you plan to do now, Laal?
I'll go to Aunt Manjeet's house from here.
From tomorrow, back to duty.
Beyond that, I don't know.
Laal, ask them to discharge you
from the Army.
Come home.
Okay.
Good.
Call me when you get back to camp.
Bless you.
Bye.
Take care.
Rupa!
Where are you going, sir?
Sir!
Rupa!
-Is everyone here?
-Yes. They're waiting for you.
-Thank you.
-Welcome.
-Oh, no!
-Laal?
-Laal!
-Hey!
Hey!
Hey, stop it!
-How dare you…
-Laal!
Laal!
Boss, he's from the Army.
It could get messy.
-Who's he?
-My childhood friend.
He's crazy.
He doesn't know who you are.
-Let him go.
-He shouldn't have hit you.
Keep quiet. You don't know anything.
Let's go.
He shouldn't have hit you.
Shut up, Laal!
Let him go, love, forgive him.
You're lucky…
I respect the Army.
Come, love. Let's go.
-Sir, what happened? Are you okay?
-Not now.
You've come to your aunt's after so long,
and you haven't said a word.
Is everything okay?
Hello.
Rupa! It's been so long!
Yes, Laal's right here.
Talk to him.
Hello.
Laal…
he's gone out with friends.
He will be back in the morning.
Can you meet me at India Gate?
Yes. Okay.
Do you know how dangerous he is?
You shouldn't have hit him.
He shouldn't have hit you, Rupa.
He looks after me well.
I'm going to be the heroine
in his next film.
It's just that he has anger issues.
I would never treat you like that.
I know, Laal.
I wanted to be your boyfriend.
Looking good… in uniform.
Handsome.
With you, after so many years,
back in Delhi…
it feels nice.
It does.
We walked all night.
Rupa and I.
We were talking all night.
She told me that she
worked in top-notch films.
Traveled the world.
Met many famous people.
Everyone respected her a lot.
She said that she was very happy.
She was enjoying life.
She was living a first-class life.
A night like this may never come again
One that brings us together
I want to gaze at you
From up close, all night
Don't want to let you go, not this time
I want you to stay
Are you really here with me?
Or is this a dream?
I don't trust my eyes
Why don't you tell me?
Once again, I yearn to tell you
How I feel about you
A night like this may never come again
One that brings us together
I should go now.
We're leaving for Dubai today.
You shouldn't go to Dubai.
-Then where should I go?
-Come home.
Why are you so good to me, Laal?
Because you're my Rupa.
I will always be your Rupa.
Don't want to let you go
Not this time
I want you to stay
Then, once again,
Rupa walked out of my life.
And I went back to the Army.
In the Army, I traveled the world
for a year with the running team.
You were given a medal
by your government!
For saving me?!
Mohammad Paaji!
A dimwit like you
was awarded by your government.
Yes.
And now you travel abroad
on government funds?!
Yes.
What a fine government!
How are you, Mohammad Paaji?
Still very much a cripple.
I spotted my savior…
and thought I should
curse him to his face…
with my choicest abuses.
Mohammad Paaji lived in a small room.
Someone sponsored a phone booth
at the airport for him to operate.
He found it inappropriate
to hurl abuses at me in public,
so he took me to his house.
Paaji, is this where you live? In Mumbai?
Well, I tried desperately to go back home.
I really did.
They disowned the dead.
How would they accept a living man?
Why?
I was no longer of use to them.
Listen to me carefully.
God has prepared such a heaven for you…
where there are 72 heavenly companions
for each and every man.
Heavenly companions with skin so sheer
that you can see right through
to the marrow of their bones.
There's God's word,
and then those who interpret it.
And fools like us forget God
and get swayed.
Did you know who I was…
when you saved me?
Tell me.
Did you know who I was?
No.
I was the enemy, you fool!
I was there to kill you…
and to be martyred in glory.
See my cursed luck!
My own enemy carried me to safety…
trying to save my legless torso.
Buy me a drink, Mr. Laal.
Isn't it a good plan?
Bala said I'd handle manufacturing
and he'd handle marketing.
But he isn't here anymore.
So, now, I'll do both.
You… will start a business?!
Of undergarments?
Manufacturing and marketing?
Yes. I had promised Bala in Kargil.
We're partners, you see.
Meet him. Laal Singh Chaddha.
Naik Laal Singh Chaddha.
Millionaire Laal Singh Chaddha.
Businessman Laal Singh Chaddha…
whose marketing manager died
even before the business started.
Good Lord!
Laal, if you become a manufacturer,
I'll become your marketing manager.
That's great.
Fool! The day you become a businessman,
I'll play football.
Friends, the new year comes
with new hope.
A chance for a new beginning.
-Let's welcome…
-A chance for a new beginning, my foot!
Everyone, with me,
-in ten, nine, eight, seven,
-…nine, eight, seven,
-six, five, four,
-three, two,
-In all that noise,
-one…
-I suddenly thought of Rupa.
I started thinking…
how must she be
celebrating New Year's Eve.
Rupa.
You shouldn't go to Dubai.
Then where should I go?
Come home.
Why are you so good to me, Laal?
Because you're my Rupa.
Lost in your thoughts, Laal?
Happy new year!
Happy new year, Mohammad Paaji.
After getting discharged from the Army,
I went back home.
Mom was very happy.
Laal.
So was I.
My son!
A short while later,
I felt like I should visit Bala's family.
So, I made a trip to Bodipalem.
Bala's village.
I met his wife.
His tattaya passed away.
Tattaya?
Grandfather.
Oh, his mother's father?
Yes.
And I don't know anything about tailoring.
See this, Mom.
It's lovely.
The villagers had made
a memorial to Bala.
I went to pay my respects.
Look, Bala, your book.
It's safe with me.
I haven't forgotten my promise.
I have the initial investment
of 100,000…
and I've spoken to Mom for the rest.
Don't you worry, my brother!
And guess where our factory
is being set up!
In Rupa's old room.
I wrote to Rupa and Mohammad Paaji
that I was starting the business.
I bought three machines,
fabric,
and I hired two tailors.
I stitched 20 sets a day,
and they stitched ten each.
That's 40 sets every day.
We made 1000 sets in a month.
Exactly as Bala had planned.
Bala was really smart.
Everything was working out
exactly as he had planned.
We enjoyed making undergarments,
so we just kept on making them.
However, what he had written
on the last page wasn't happening.
We weren't able to sell 800 sets a month.
Son, I know to farm.
But I have no idea about
the undergarments business.
And then, one day, guess who turned up!
Thank you.
Mohammad Paaji!
What brings you here?
I thought I'd work on a sewing machine.
But Paaji, you don't have legs.
I know, you fool.
You wrote to me.
Bala Undergarments, right?
Very good.
-You've actually become a businessman.
-Yes!
So, I'm here to be
your marketing manager.
I'm a man of my word, Laal.
Where's the stock?
Not a single set has sold?!
We have sold five sets.
Mom bought them. For me.
Mohammad Paaji gave me an idea.
We started
a "Buy one, get one free" offer.
We still didn't sell anything.
So, he suggested
a "Buy one, get two free" offer.
We still didn't sell anything,
so we tried
"Buy one, get three free."
When we still didn't sell anything,
we stopped production.
Oh my God!
Give me a pen.
Oh, God!
Woman!
Our product needs a woman's name!
How can we do that?
It's a man's product.
What do men want, Laal?
Women! Write!
Write a woman's name!
Write it, Laal!
Sorry, Bala, my brother.
I knew only one woman's name.
The sweetest name in the world.
Rupa.
Game on, Laal! Now watch!
And then… a miracle happened.
Our product actually started selling.
Rupa Undergarments.
And just like that, we grew
from three machines to nine machines.
Then we moved to a bigger place.
After that to an even bigger place.
Today, we have many factories,
and our head office is in Delhi.
Smile, please.
Our product is very popular.
Maybe you are wearing it too.
Yes.
Hold on a minute.
Are you saying that you are
the owner of Rupa Corporation?
Yes.
Very good.
Madam, we're in the company
of a millionaire.
In a second-class, non-AC compartment.
Rupa Corporation!
Liar!
What an engaging story, son.
And you tell it so nicely.
Thank you.
Would you like to see a photo
of Mohammad Paaji?
Sure.
-Here.
-Let me see it.
-India Today featured us on their cover.
-Wow.
Wow!
Show me.
We won an award a few years ago.
Entrepreneur of the Year.
Isn't Mohammad Paaji
looking smart in a suit?
Rupa Corporation!
Yes, Rupa Corporation.
I split the profits of Rupa Corporation
into two halves.
Mohammad Paaji calls me a fool,
but every year, one-half
of the profit goes to Bala's wife.
-Chithra!
-Is that in lakhs?
-No, in crores.
Mohammad Paaji invested
my profits in some cowshed.
He says I never have to worry
about money again.
Mohammad Paaji is a very good man.
After Mom, Bala, and Rupa,
he is my closest friend.
…was heard
at Chhatrapati Shivaji Terminus.
Lashkar-e-Taiba terrorists
have held the city hostage
with gunfire and bombings for 60 hours.
They have killed more than 175 civilians
and critically injured over 300.
Ismail Khan was killed by the police,
but Ajmal Kasab was captured alive.
According to sources,
Kasab is only 21 years old.
Laal.
I never thanked you…
for saving me.
Thank you, Laal.
Welcome, Paaji.
Laal.
I've never seen you pray.
No rituals,
no offering prayers.
How come?
My Mom says that…
religion sometimes causes malaria.
And God resides within each of us.
Within Mom, within me,
within you.
Mohammad Paaji, aren't you going home?
I was thinking the same, Laal.
It's time I went home.
I was told the enemy lives here.
Non-believers.
Then I found you.
I tried to kill you.
And you tried to save me.
I believed this to be an enemy country.
Instead, I found a friend.
You know, Laal…
I was suffering from malaria myself.
You saved me.
But malaria is still being spread there.
Many like me are being brainwashed.
Being taught to hate.
Laal…
I want to go back and start a school.
I want to teach children
about friends like you here.
Paaji, I'll write letters to you.
Thank you, Laal.
Thank you.
And then, one day, Mohammad Paaji left.
But before leaving,
he hired a lot of smart people
to look after Rupa Corporation.
Good morning, sir.
Along with Bala and Rupa,
I now started missing Mohammad Paaji too.
-Hello.
-Sir, it's Bahadur. I'm calling from home.
Mom is really unwell.
Please come quickly.
Laal.
Come, sit.
What happened, Mom?
Nothing, son.
It's just time for me to go.
Why are you going?
Because my time here is over, Laal.
There's no need to worry.
Everyone has to leave someday.
This is completely natural.
Death is also a part of life.
I was lucky to have you in my life.
But this is where
we are meant to part ways.
I did my best.
I got some things right.
Maybe I even got some things wrong.
Please don't go.
Don't go, Mom.
I wish.
Life is like golgappas, Laal.
Your tummy may be full…
but your heart always craves more.
Look after yourself, okay?
Mom had cancer.
She died on a Thursday.
Mom used to say…
"The Lord wants you
to keep only what you need
and give the rest to those in need."
So, I built a hospital in Mom's name.
Our family doctor takes care of it.
There, everyone is treated free of cost.
After my mom's death, there was
no one to take care of the farm.
If I had gone back to the factory,
what would have become
of the farm workers?
So, I didn't go back.
I started farming.
During the day,
work would keep me busy.
But as night would fall,
memories of Rupa would torment me.
It had been many years
since I had seen Rupa.
I missed her terribly.
Rupa!
And then, one day, she came back.
Just like that!
I cleaned up Mom's room for her.
I think she was very tired.
For the first few days,
all she did was sleep…
all day, all night.
I told her everything.
Bala, Mohammad Paaji,
the factory, and Rupa Corporation.
I told her that she need not worry
about money anymore.
I could give her all she wanted.
But she didn't seem to care
about money anymore.
She remained quiet most of the time.
Except once, when our
home help was drunk
and was beating his wife…
she got angry.
She beat him
and then started crying herself.
For very long.
Rupa, that's enough. Stop it.
Enough.
It's okay, Rupa.
And then, one day, Rupa smiled.
We used to work together in the fields.
We were together all the time.
Just like carrots and peas.
I had got back my magician…
who could pluck out a plane
from the sky and stuff it in her pocket.
She taught me to dance.
It felt like the two of us were a family.
She was the mother,
and I was the father.
I have never felt such joy in my life.
That year, on Diwali,
she gave me the best gift.
Shoes.
And that night…
Rupa…
will you marry me?
I'll take very good care of you.
I know, Laal.
But you won't marry me.
Because I'm not smart.
I'm stupid. Isn't that it?
No, Laal. It's not that.
I can't marry you because--
Because I can't be relied upon.
I may not be smart,
but I…
I know what love is.
Laal.
Laal…
I love you…
very much.
That's the truth.
I'm here.
Don't wake him.
Let's go.
Here one moment
Gone the next
You've been mine
Only in fragments
My life's story
Has many chapters
You are a part
Of every one of them
I started running.
I'm not sure why.
I just felt like running.
I ran to the main road.
Then I thought I'd run to the market.
I reached the market
and thought I'd run to the city.
After crossing the city,
I thought, "Let me run some more."
I ran so far ahead…
that I had covered half the state.
So, I thought I might as well
run across all of it.
I didn't feel like stopping.
From that day onward, I kept running.
I kept running.
-Anna Hazare! We are with you!
Here, at the Ram Leela Ground,
Anna Hazare has been
on a hunger strike for the past 12 days,
pushing for the anti-corruption
Jan Lokpal Bill,
with massive citizen support.
Hey! Who's this guy? Such an idiot!
Who was that?
Why didn't you stop him? Fool!
-Hail Anna Hazare!
We've just heard that Anna Hazare
has ended his hunger strike.
I reached the sea and turned around.
Then I reached another sea.
Again, I turned around.
When I reached the mountains,
I turned around.
I just kept running.
Welcome to Samaj Sanchar!
First, let's hear today's breaking news!
The police have captured
underworld don Abbas Haji in Malaysia.
Let me remind you that a few months ago,
Abbas Haji's girlfriend,
Rupa D'Souza was arrested
from a small village in Punjab.
With the information she provided,
Abbas has been arrested today.
I thought a lot…
about Mom,
Bala, Mohammad Paaji…
but mostly…
about Rupa.
You are the seeker
You are also the messiah
You are the circus
And also the ringmaster
You wander in vain
In shrines and temples
The one that you seek
Is within you
Why do you torment yourself?
Didn't the pain of separation scar you?
Walk alone, O crazy one, walk alone
Leave the streets of sadness behind
Walk alone
Walk alone, O crazy one, walk alone
Leave the streets of sadness behind
Walk alone
Welcome to Samaj Sanchar!
Let's hear today's breaking news!
The Mumbai High Court
has given its verdict
on the Abbas Haji and Rupa D'Souza case.
Abbas Haji was arrested
with the help of model Rupa D'Souza.
Abbas Haji gets a life sentence
for five murders,
and considering her role as the approver,
Rupa D'Souza is sentenced
to only six months.
Now, let's meet a strange man
who's been running across the country.
Mr. Laal Singh,
are you running for world peace?
Are you running for women's rights?
Are you running for the environment?
One day, some TV reporters
started filming me.
Sir! It's you!
I saw you running on TV.
I told my wife, "This guy is special."
Sir, I told her that you know everything.
Sir, I want to run with you
wherever you go.
So, this guy started running with me.
Then some more people joined me.
And then some more.
They said that I gave them hope.
Well, I don't know about that.
I was just running.
Take it for the truth
A true lover is the one
Who can set their beloved free
The lover who can seek blessings
-For the one who broke their heart
A single teardrop of such a lover
Would cause even a desert to bloom
Walk alone, O crazy one, walk alone
Leave the streets of sadness behind
Walk alone
Your love is wild and carefree
Break free of your cage and fly
The horizon where earth and sky meet
Beyond the fiery sunset
That is your destination, O traveler
Walk alone, O crazy one, walk alone
Mom used to say,
"The past is best left behind."
Maybe that's why I was running.
I ran for four years, seven months,
two weeks, and three days.
He's stopped.
Maybe he'll say something.
Quiet!
Mr. Laal Singh is going to speak.
Mr. Laal Singh, why have you stopped?
I'm tired.
I'm going back home.
Hey, turn around.
As you just saw,
Mr. Laal Singh is tired.
He's going back home.
Stay tuned for stories like this…
What a crazy fellow!
He isn't crazy.
I started to look a bit like my grandpas.
It made me happy.
He is the one Lord
The eternal truth
The creator and doer
Devoid of fear or enmity
Omnipresent
He's unborn, self-existent
Attained by the Guru's grace
Chant…
The primal truth
The truth through the ages
The present truth
O Nanak, forever true
You can't fathom Him, no matter how much
You ponder over Him
You may focus on Him
But you can't attain the perfect silence
All the material pleasures of the world
Will not satiate your hunger
However wise you may be
You take nothing with you in the end
How to attain the Truth?
How to rip apart this veil of delusion?
Nanak writes that only
His will can carry you through
Sir…
when you were out,
these letters came from Ms. Rupa.
She even called many times.
Look, these are Rupa's letters.
She's called me to Chandigarh.
Wow!
-She saw me running on TV.
-Very good.
Uncle, Chandigarh has arrived.
-Gosh!
-Take this.
Please move.
-Bye.
Good luck!
-Bless me.
-God bless you.
-I'll take your leave. Bye.
-Bye!
-Bye, Uncle.
-Give my regards to Rupa!
-Bye!
-Bye! All the best!
CLEAN RAIL, CLEAN INDIA
ONE STEP TOWARD CLEANLINESS
Laal.
Hi!
Hello.
When did you start wearing a turban?
You're looking so good.
Come in.
I've got golgappas for you.
I ate a few on the way though.
I was hungry.
That's okay.
And…
I got the spiced water separately.
Have a seat.
Isn't this from Delhi?
Yes.
I saw you running on TV.
Yes, I ran a lot.
Me too.
Laal…
I feel like I've treated you badly.
Very badly.
But…
I treated myself even worse.
Everything was wrong.
But now, it's all right.
Mom.
You're up, son?
Come here.
Meet my best friend.
Say hello.
Hello, Uncle.
Hello.
Mom, can I watch cartoons?
Yes, go.
You've become a mother?!
Yes, I've become a mother.
What's his name?
Aman.
Aman Chaddha.
He's also a Chaddha?!
Yes, because his father is a Chaddha.
Laal Singh Chaddha.
His father's name is also
Laal Singh Chaddha?!
Laal…
you are his father.
Laal, listen to me.
Relax, Laal.
You didn't do anything wrong, Laal.
Laal, look at me.
Look at me.
It's all good.
Okay?
Isn't he the cutest?
Yes, he is.
Just adorable.
But is he smart, or…
-is he like me--
-Laal…
He's very smart.
The brightest in his class.
Can I…
can I go to him?
Of course. Go.
Go.
Laal…
I'm sick.
What happened?
I don't know.
The doctors haven't diagnosed it yet.
Come home with me.
I'll take care of you.
Laal…
will you marry me?
I am colored now, forever
In the color of your love
In our union
Two souls
Have become one
I found God
When I found you
By my side
Even though you weren't by my side
You were with me every moment
To be with you
I would wait an eternity
Even though you weren't by my side
You were with me every moment
To be with you
I would wait an eternity
All that I have
I surrender to you
Every atom of my being
Is yours
All that I have
I surrender to you
Every atom of my being
Is yours
I am colored now, forever
In the color of your love
In our union
Two souls
Have become one
I found God
When I found you
By my side
Laal,
were you scared when you were in Kargil?
Yes.
But at night,
when the Himalayas would glow,
I would feel really nice.
And in Kanyakumari,
when I saw the sunset…
it looked like a million stars
were twinkling in the ocean.
When I was running in Ladakh,
it felt like there were two skies.
And in the twilight of the desert…
as I was counting the stars…
I forgot who I was,
and what I was doing there.
It was so serene and peaceful.
I wish I had been there with you then.
You were there…
with me.
I love you, Laal.
Today's your death anniversary.
How are you?
I'm fine.
Aman's also fine.
He's such a good kid.
He does all his work on his own.
He's going to start school from tomorrow.
Our old school.
I'm teaching him to play table tennis.
And to sew.
If you were here,
you'd have taught him
to catch airplanes.
He reads me stories.
He's very smart.
He's written you a letter.
I'm not allowed to read it.
You read it…
later.
He misses you a lot.
I do too.
Mom used to say,
"Each of us has our own destiny."
Mohammad Paaji too says…
that everything is predestined.
I don't know…
where all this is written,
who wrote it,
or why it is written in the first place.
Whatever happens,
is it in our control?
Or are we just drifting in the wind…
blown from here to there?
I have no idea.
Perhaps a bit of both.
Had you been here,
you would've explained it to me.
I…
I miss you, Rupa.
I really miss you.
Son, you have to work very hard.
You have to do better than your best.
Yes, Dad.
-Shall I go?
-Yes, Dad.
-Sure?
Okay, I'll come to get you in the evening.
-Bye-bye, Dad.
-Bye.
-Aman.
-Yes, Dad?
-I love you, my son.
-I love you, Dad.
Off you go.
Do the lines on your palm
Determine your fate?
Or do you mold your destiny
With your own hands?
Are we smart enough to understand life?
Or is it wiser not to?